op--
蟲砕銃
一丁上がりだね
赤色貫通弾
死ね死ね死ね死ね*N
Insect-Smashing Bug:
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Crimson Piercing Round!
Die! Die! Die!
I win.
Insect Magistrate, I'll kill you!
蟲奉行　殺す
Earthquake Hammer!
大鯰槌
Matsunohara!
松ノ原
Insect Magistrate!
蟲奉行様
What enormous power...
なんてバカ力なの
He shattered a mountain!
山を砕いちゃうなんて
Tenma!
天間
お一人で逃げてください　蟲奉行様
Please escape on your own, Magistrate!
い　いやじゃ
I will not.
今度はわらわの番なのじゃ
This time, it is my turn.
一人では逃げぬ
I will not escape alone...
Let's go, Tsukishima!
行くぞ　月島
We shall return to Edo together,
一緒に江戸に帰ろうぞ
Tsukishima.
月島　月島
Tsukishima!
Jinbei's Power Awakens!!
【目覚めた力　仁兵衛　覚醒】
Before long, they'll catch up.
追手が来るのも時間の問題
急がねば
I must hurry!
Please don't die!
頼む　決して死ぬではないぞ
わらわはまだお主に謝罪しておらぬ…
I still have yet to apologize...
Tsukishima!
月島　大事はないか
Are you hurt?
月島
Tsukishima?
お主が敵だと勘ぐるなど
I am such a horrible woman
for thinking you the enemy.
わらわは最低のことをした
To protect me, you were
prepared to sacrifice your life.
お主は命を捨てる覚悟で　わらわを守ってくれていたのに
You did all you could for me.
あんなにも　わらわに尽くしてくれたというのに
お主はここで死んではならんぞ
You must not die here!
You must live!
必ず生きるのじゃ
And I beg you...
そして　どうかわらわにすまなかったと言わせておくれ
Give me the chance to apologize!
甲脚
Armor Kick!
What's wrong, Mugai?
どうした　無涯　随分と落ち着きがなくなったな
You're starting to look worried.
Are you so concerned about the Insect Magistrate?
そんなに蟲奉行のことが心配か
It's over!
もういいだろう
もう黒揚羽の能力は殺した
We've neutralized Kuroageha's powers...
今や蟲奉行はただの小娘だ
Now the Insect Magistrate is but a girl!
And by now, she's already dead.
それに今頃　もう死んでるさ
I sent him to finish her.
あいつに始末を任せたからな
あいつ　蒼願は
That man...
Sougan.
He's more dedicated to the mission
than any other Insect Hunter.
俺たち蟲狩のどれよりも使命に忠実だ
例えば真白なら　蟲奉行に罵声を浴びながら蹴り殺すだろう
Mashiro would kick and swear
at her until she died.
至胴なら　肉の塊になるまで刺し続けるだろう
Shidou would stab her until she
was just unmoving flesh.
However, he is different.
だが　あいつは違う
I seek neither screams, pain nor despair.
俺は悲鳴も苦痛も絶望も　何も求めない
Nothing.
I merely seek your descent into hell.
ただ貴様が地獄に落ちれば　それでいい
さらば
Farewell!
ここで死ぬというのか
Am I going to die here?
わらわはまだ月島に謝っていないというのに
I still haven't apologized to Tsukishima...
月島
Tsukishima...
Tsukishima?
Child...
わっぱ
き　貴様
You...
Tsukishima?
月島　月島なのか
Is that you, Tsukishima?
He looks and feels like an
utterly different person.
出で立ちも雰囲気も　まるで別人ではないか
Above all, he's strong!
何より　強い
以前は一方的にやられたというのに
During the last fight, he was helpless.
Who are you?
お前は一体何者なのだ
わっぱ　貴様を殺すのが先決のようだな
It seems I must kill you first, child.
この煉獄槍は　ねを回すほど火力の高い爆発を起こす
The more times I turn Purgatory's
Spear, the greater its explosion.
そして最大の出力になると
And at maximum power,
その代償として俺の両腕さえも焼けきれる
its explosion will blow off my arms.
But for our mission's sake,
I will gladly use it on you.
だが　我らの目的のため
喜んで貴様にくれてやるぞ
They're nearby.
いる
What?
いる　敵がたくさん
They're nearby.
Many enemies.
こ　こいつ
H-He's...
He isn't even thinking about me?
俺は　すでに眼中に入っていない
何なのだ　こいつは一体
What is he?
そしてなぜ
And why?
Why can't I stop shaking?
震えが止まらないのだ
危険すぎる
This is too dangerous.
今ここで殺しておかねば
I must kill him here,
even if it costs my life.
わが命を捨ててでも
煉獄槍　獄炎
Purgatory's Spear: Hellfire!
I've failed...
無念
蒼願
I see.
Damn it! What happened?
くそが　何が起きてんだよ
真白　至胴 お前たちは下に加勢に向かえ
Mashiro! Shidou! Get down there and help.
Don't let Sougan's death be in vain!
蒼願の死を　無駄にするな
Roger.
了解
さあ　これで二人っきりだ
Now, then... It's just the two of us.
Mugai,
無涯　なぜ俺たち蟲狩を裏切った
why did you betray the Insect Hunters?
That night, you went alone to kill the Magistrate.
一人で蟲奉行を殺しに行ったあの夜
What happened?
何があった
When we were kids,
we did everything together.
俺たちはガキの頃から　何をするでも一緒で
それ中じゃ　貴様は誰よりも信頼されてた
And everyone trusted you the most.
Much more than they trusted me...
俺よりも　ずっとな
だというのに　貴様はなぜ蟲奉行側についた
So why did you join her?
貴様はあの方から聞いたはずだ
You heard them say
俺たちの里を滅ぼしたのは蟲奉行だと
that it was the Insect Magistrate
who destroyed our village.
Tell me, my little brother...
なぁ　弟
気安く弟などと呼ぶな 蟲狩
Don't you dare call me "brother,"
Insect Hunter!
月島
Tsukishima?
Tsukishima!
I'll just h-have to...
とにかく　連続突っ張り
Multi-Slap!
Die!
死ね
What bad luck...
ついてないな
こんなところまで土砂で流されるなんて
I can't believe the mudslide
took me so far down.
それに
Also...
Do I really have to fight this guy?
この人の相手　僕がするの
ていてないな
What bad luck...
邪魔者　全部殺す
Kill everyone in my way!
やった
Did we get him?
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
させないよ
I won't let you.
Insect-Smashing Bug:
蟲砕銃　赤色貫通弾
Crimson Piercing Round!
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
じゃ　まずお前から
Then, I'll start with you.
死ねよ
Die...
Sorry I'm late.
待たせちまったな
恋川
Koikawa...
道が悪くてよ
The road here sucked.
Did you think you could win?
勝ってるとでも思ったか
まとめて討ってやる
Let's kill them all.
俺がやる
I'll do it...
He's still alive?
生きてやがったのか
しぶといのよ　クソガキ
That stupid kid's tough.
俺は鉄丸だ
I am Kuroganemaru!
クソガキじゃねぇんだよ
I'm not a stupid kid!
蟲砕銃
Insect-Smashing Bug:
Crimson Piercing Round!
赤色貫通弾
Die! Die! Die! Die! Die!
死ね死ね死ね死ね死ね*N
Die! Die! Die!
死ーね！
一丁上がりだね
I win.
T-Tsukishima?
つ　月島
月島
Tsukishima?
He's serious!
こいつ　マジだ
Why?
なぜだ
Now Tsukishima seems more like
me or the Insect Hunters...
今の月島はまるでわらわや蟲狩のよう
What happened to the
Tsukishima who smiled at me?
わらわに笑いかけてくれた　あの月島は…
一体どこにいったのじゃ
ちょっと　月島
Hey, Tsukishima!
あんた　何してんのよ
What are you doing?
Don't you know who we are?
私達のこと　分からないの
Looks like he won't listen to us.
何を言っても無駄みてぇだな
あいつヤバイよ
That guy's dangerous!
Yeah.
He finally remembered us?
やっと私達に気付いて
いや　あの顔見ろよ
No, look at his face...
He's just more interested in
them than he is in us.
俺らよりあいつらに興味が移っただけだ
早っ
Fast!
こいつ
Take this!
He's gone...
いない
こら　クソガキ
Take this, stupid kid!
Don't let him humiliate us again, guys!
野郎共　これ以上なめられるな
Tsukishima!
月島
I can't breathe!
苦しい
What's happened to you, man?
兄ちゃん　一体どうなってんだ
At this rate, Tsukishima will destroy himself...
このままでは　月島が壊れてしまう
I have to stop him somehow!
何とか止めなければ
Everyone is my enemy...
全員　敵
Enemies must be defeated!
敵は倒す
逃げろ
Run!
Tsukishima, you idiot!
このバカ月島
Wh-What is this?
これは…
I don't know what I can do now.
今のわらわに何かできるか分からぬ
でもこれ以上　月島のあのような姿は　見とおない
But I don't want to see
Tsukishima this way any longer!
Yo...
You have such a pretty face.
綺麗な顔しやがって
Be happy.
喜べ
I'm going to rip it apart.
気の済むまでぐちゃぐちゃにしてやるよ
月島
Tsukishima!
すまぬな
I'm sorry...
江戸の空をともに見る約束
I won't be able to keep my promise
to see the Edo skies with you!
果たせそうにない
すまぬな
I'm sorry.
約束
Promise!
お　お付の方
M-Miss...
ご無事ですか
Are you okay?
T-Tsukishima?
つ　月島
蟲奉行様の元へ急ぎましょう
Let's hurry to the Insect Magistrate!
And also,
約束を
keep our promise...
果たしに
月島
Tsukishima?
We're withdrawing.
引き上げるぞ
The Magistrate is powerless
and can be killed at our leisure.
無力な蟲奉行なんざいつでもやれる
My hair?
わらわの髪
月島の変貌と何か関係が
Does this have something to
do with his transformation?
Magistrate!
蟲奉行様
J-J-Jinbei-kun...
仁　仁　仁　仁兵衛君
何て無礼なことを
How disrespectful...
After all that, you're napping on her lap?!
散々暴れて　今度は膝枕
さっさと退け
Get off!
What are you doing?
これ　何をする
I need to look into Jinbei-kun.
仁兵衛君のことは調べないといけないけど
But for now...
とにかく
The Insect Magistrate's Office,
City Patrol, has completed its mission!
これにて　蟲奉行所市中見廻り組
恙無く　任務を全うせり
いつの日か　今よりも　強くなりたい
ただ一つの願い　胸に咲く炎
何もできなかった日に　胸の誓いは生まれた
決してもう逃げださないと　ただひたすら前を向くと
傷つき倒れ　また立ち上がる　諦めなど知らぬものに
春は何度でも
この先に何がある　見えなくていい
一途なまなざしが　炎を灯すよ
あの若侍は
Who is that young samurai?
何者でござろうか
I've no interest in a dog serving
one who disrespects our lord.
賊軍に尾を振る犬などに興味はない
Princess,
姫君
程なくわが王はお目覚めになりまする
the King will soon awaken.
今暫し　ご辛抱を
Wait just a little longer.
When the awakening occurs,
then I, Sanada Yukimura,
お目覚めの暁には
この真田幸村
Sanada Yukimura
必ずあなたをお城に奉る
shall escort you to the castle.
Sarutobi Sasuke
The Ten Crucifix Insects of Sanada
We return to the tower where
our lord waits, Sasuke.
戻るぞ　佐助
王の待つ　天守閣へ
Next Time
The softness, whiteness, roundness,
あの柔らかさ　白さ　丸さ
their size and feel in your hands...
大きくてむっちりの感触　早く味わいたい
I can't wait to taste them...
はぁ？
The dumplings at Oharu-san's restaurant!
春夏秋冬のお団子
O-Of course.
そ　そうね
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行「父との修行！富嶽三十六剣！！」
Training with Father.
Training with Father!
The Thirty-six Blades of Fuji!!
The Thirty-six Blades of Fuji.